morning you coming in
then good morning and what a show we've
got lined up for you today we really
have I'll be joining the house
throughout the morning by the comedian
Lee Francis
here and we've got Sue Cleaver swapping
the cob coration street from seat of my
kitchen table both have never been on
the show before and we join a pair and
raspberry kumble C my old pal from my
ready City cook days Paul ranking is
here as well and I'll be tasting some of
Spain's finest cheeses another one of my
favorite ever food adventures and don't
miss this week's mastercast we're
teaching you a brilliant recipe using
place and that's not all because we join
a dish later on this morning from a top
chef who has created two of Britain's
best pubs around his hometown of Tavo
it's the brilliant Mr John
hooker welcome back Chief great to be
here pal um so we're going to start off
the show really we're get to kick things
off with a couple of recipes U using
these amazing leaks which we're going to
celebrate from A supplier in
Lincolnshire that I'm going to introduce
you to in a bit but I'm going to do
these two recipes at Ace one of which is
my favorite the other one is I I found
on my little spot of Spanish Adventure
little tap pass sort of dish but the
first thing we do is take our bacon so
this is for the so the tapy sort of one
so we take the the bacon like that I'm
going to basically into little
lons and then all I'm going to do is fry
this off cuz the important thing is with
this we actually use the Bacon Fat to
make the dressing as well so you use a
little bit of vegetable oil and we're
going to fry off this little bit of
bacon so you get it nice and crisp in
here I'm going to take the other part of
the leaks and we're going to do leaks
baked in Brios with which I absolutely
adore it's one of my favorite things
with cheese on the top it tastes but
we're going to cut these
leaks and chop them all up and they're
just going to go in the pan with some
fresh Brios I've got over here Touch of
cream some white wine some fresh thyme
and these gets toasted and roasted and
everything else and these are going to
go in the oven with a little little bit
of cheese as well over the top so while
these are cooking and while my Bacon's
cooking why don't we head off to a farm
on the edge of arth connley in
lincolshire to speak to Tim Casey from
bomber County produce welcome to the
show
Tim good morning James thank you yeah
now thank you for coming on and thank
you for being standing in the middle of
the field as well to show us where this
produce come from so first of all how
did it all start cuz you're you're what
fourth
generation uh yeah it's well there
there's four generations on on the farm
although um the youngest aren aren't uh
fully employed they're still at school
but they do plenty of school holiday
stuff you got the word you forgot the
word yet there was uh my granddad uh
started off when he was in the RAF based
here on lancasters in the second world
war a rear Gunner met Manan they set up
here so they got a little bit of land
and uh expanded a little bit and then my
dad came into the farm um and in the 70s
they bought their own farm that they
could actually Farm outright on and and
uh they grew it from there and in the
'90s
1991 they started growing leaks and uh
we're still growing them now so I'm
going to take the onions that's going to
go in the pan with the bacon we're just
going to soften the onion so you don't
you fry up the bacon till it's crispy
and soping the onions in here but like I
said the fat is the key part of this to
make the dressing so I've got the leaks
cooking away nicely over here with some
fresh thyme and in there we're going to
have some white wine Brios and put the
cheese on the top keep it really nice
and Light but this is what we do with
this we pass it through a c so we get
this amazing oil from it as
well that goes in there so tell me about
leak production then because I didn't
realize how labor intensive it is yeah I
think you can see behind me we' got some
guys working really hard and the
conditions today are awful uh with the
amount of rain that we've had um so yeah
it it's it's really hard hard graft it
really is you got to pull them by hand
then trim them up and then we put them
through a wash and bring them back chill
them and then give them a little trim
and then pack them
out and your fa your father's still
doing this and he your your parents are
still involved in the farm still working
on the
farm yeah yeah my dad is specially is
very active and he's 73 now in fact 74 I
think um yeah he he he works as hard as
anyone um yeah and I didn't realize as
well when I was doing a little bit of
research before I was talking to you
that that leaks you the predominantly uh
some of which you produce on site and
you grow them for seedlings but a lot of
them you bring in from uh Morocco and
Spain and in warmer climates and bring
them in and plant them as sort of little
shoots well yeah it's it's it's the
early production so to try and get the
uh early start to the season in the
summer when we start harvesting in July
we'll bring plants from Morocco or Spain
that have been uh propagated quite early
on in well climates that are far more
suitable they get brought open we plant
them out in the field and and they're
ready earlier than what we can do at
just solely from UK glass houses or from
seed but then we'll go right through
till uh the end of April beginning of
May um harvesting and we can store and
for a few weeks and keep keep supplying
British Leakes into May and June what
about you as a king Gardener are you
deviled into the Garden or not my wife's
grandfather is a very keen Gardener with
he's got poly tunnels he's he's in his
70s and he's right into it and it's just
it's a lot of hard work and passion that
goes into growing stuff isn't it well
well leaks particularly because I've had
I've had good success with leaks some
years and then other years nothing what
what what what do you need I mean
obviously where you live this the soil
what what is this special about where
you are in the production of leaks well
it it's h the soil is really important
we've got nice sandy soil here which
makes it easier for getting on in the
spring and then also easier getting them
off in the winter but it's uh yeah you
also it doesn't want to be uh too wet uh
because leaks don't like wet feet but at
the same time they still need a lot of
uh irrigation or rain to grow a little
of water so you got to have good
irrigation as well but look hopefully
I'm doing this Justice over here Sim you
can see this this is this this is a
perfect dish when you come back from the
field really but this is leaks this is
Brios it's cheese Got Cream I've got
some white wine in here and I'm going to
do is pop it in here to Brown the other
leaks are we're going to do with this
dressing so I've toasted the hazelnuts
this is the the uh onions with that but
the leaks I'm got in here all we do with
these leaks is you just take the entire
lot and put it straight on the coals I
don't know where you ever cooked leaks
like this but you just put them straight
on the barbecue on the coals and you
blacken the skin and when you blacken
the skin and you take take them off it
ends up like this because leaks like you
said you mentioned moisture and water
they contain tons of water and you can
utilize that to create the steam to cook
the
leaks so these just got I don't know
whether you've had this Tim cooked on
the barbecue just simple like
this no I I've actually have not tried
them like that but that just goes to
show how versatile they are well that's
the thing you just put them straight on
the coals and then when we slice them
all up they Steam
I can see he's thinking what recipe can
I put that with with with with that one
when I put it on the menu but the
dressing for this is the key to it when
you just take the leaks like this I had
this in a lovely little tapas bar in
Spain and uh it wasn't with the leaks it
was just this dressing with pork but the
dressing sort of appealed to me that I
thought it would be really good with
this you just take the leaks like that
don't mind about the little Char bits as
well you want those and then the
dressing bit over here so you take take
the bacon and the onions like that and
then the dressing bit is the key so keep
my eye on what's Happening behind me but
the dressing uses the fat from the
bacon
some dejon mustard bit of that cherry
vinegar over the top as
well touch's Hazen nut
oil we've got the hazelnuts going
through it as well this is the key to it
I was wondering what this was in Spain
and I went around the back of the
kitchen Spanish is not very good anyway
let alone oyster sauce in Spanish but
this this is what they used and these
oyster sauce you mix that looks like
quite a thick oyster sauce that James it
is but it MiFi into this creamy
dressing and then you put lemon zest in
it lemon zest a bit of lemon juice that
sits on there but just squeeze a lemon
juice some fresh herbs and that's your
dressing done add a little bit of pass
it to it and that's it and you mentioned
the fact that's so versatile as well I
mean I I take it do you have do you have
an early crop Tim or do you have a later
crop or is it they all just happen all
at once and that's where the workload
is no no well uh we we go for 11 months
of the year harvesting leaks start in
July and finish the following May time
sometimes well I wish you all the very
bested up with it I know you want to get
back to work and I'm just going to
finish this off I've done it justice as
well but thank you for joining us good
luck with everything and thank you on
behalf of the entire country for doing
what you're doing because it is hard
work very thank you very much thank you
very much good luck thank you very much
but look you just got the little
dressing over the top that's your this
is the oyster sauce the fat from the
bacon over the top and it creates this
wonderful little salad and there we have
it leaks two ways one cooked with cream
and Brios and cheese and that kind of
stuff cooked really really simple the
other one straight on the cuse and this
is how you cook it it just as it is as
the leaks go black on one side you turn
them over cook them on the other side
and all the steam all the the moisture
that's in the leaks will steam the
inside of it and cook the middle and you
just get rid of the outside easy as that
amazing
you got your eye on that one haven't you
really the barbecued leaks buzz in for
this they're uh and then these the the
the cheesy creamy leaks look really
simple keto is don't overcook the leaks
because you want the flavor from it
that's the when you have great produce
like this don't overcook it whether it's
in a soup only takes like8 minutes to
make a soup 10
minutes that's so simple but it's so
complex when you eat it like clever SMY
note I had it in a tapas bar and I
couldn't for the life of me think what
flavor it was from it and it's that bit
of oyster sauce that was with it and
it's delicious it's really nice isn't it
really unusual they have a little bit of
the creamy leaks as well to go with it
but that's with a Brios as
well really simple but delicious Super
Rich really rich as well yeah right I've
be cooking for comedian Lee Francis but
surlee and I'll be giving you Mas and
gons a little bit later but don't go
anywh cuz after after the break we' got
crumble on the menu courtesy of some
Chef called Paul Rankin you may remember
him see you in a couple of
minutes welcome back now we making
hadock fish cakes for comedian Lee
Francis in a couple of minutes and later
on I'll be sharing some Gan recipes with
this week's little Mass but first I'm
here with John and while you lot were at
home still having your breakfast we are
about to took into to a bowl of crumble
from a man whose Legend restaurant
rosoff help put Northern Ireland on the
Cy map with a Michelin star that was a
brilliant restaurant this is Mr Paul
Rankin
you good to have you back Chief yes yes
it feels it feels like you know it's 30
31 years it's hard to believe now and
it's ready I think ready St it was 32
years something like that but I have
thought it you know see my memory it's
not it's over 30 years what are you
going to be cooking then a pear crumble
this is a dish that I literally used to
do in Ros gos and of course it's pair
time of the year these are commas pairs
um so what I do is I take a little knife
and I take that out you want to do that
okay all right I'll do that take and
then we peel them yeah y cool and then
we're going we're going to cut them up a
wee bit roast them I think uh I mean you
could just put them directly in the oven
but I like to get a little bit of the
juices going get lemon juice in there
and get sugar in there now with pears
you need to be really careful I'll start
making the crumble you do the crumble
with but no I don't have a bow to make
my
crumble it was like this 30 OD years ago
but you you were telling me that you
it's always been like this this this
gentleman over here was telling me that
he he he remembers coming off from
school and seeing me and you it's like
TV royalty here today a't it like you
guys start I'm ready cook yeah of course
yeah who who was the best well it was it
it was a master in The Apprentice wasn't
it I don't know what Brian would say
about that that's all right next time
you finding up waned to be at the house
we're
busy no phenomenal phenomenal it was it
was mad didn't it like you've been going
back all those years that like well how
old were you then then 12 I wasn't even
a teenager James was he hold on can I
just start
this we can have the chat what crumble
is actually for me this is the recipe I
use and it's dead easy it's equal
volumes o o of of no it's equal weights
equal
weights it's because you give us wine
first thing in the morning you I'm not
good about wine first thing in the
morning yes sh sh flour butter and sugar
yeah so it makes it dead easy so if you
want to make a crumble just
spontaneously after dinner just remember
that so we can you you can add all sorts
of things to this we can add lemon zest
um you could add spices to it yeah what
I'm going to add is is some flaked
almonds you mentioned rosov because that
were you at the First Northern Island's
first michion star restaurant I was I'm
going to take a handful of oats and
whack it in there CU you started out but
not chasing it did you we got a I I
would say we got M Star by accident
right and that's because I was trained
with the R Brothers at gabos I spent 3
years training in a three star melin
restaurant which was my first kitchen
job
yeah and I I was so stupid I didn't I
didn't know any other way to
cook just went to London and and went
from there well knocked on the back door
I spent three years in London Then I
then I spent a a year in the Four
Seasons in Vancouver and then two years
in the Napa Valley right and then I came
back to Belfast well then you opened
rosoff after that yeah and it was
supposed to be like a brazer and we got
a misinstalled by accident they don't
just give him away well you know they
visit visited US 10 times I think before
back in those days they really did uh
and didn't you you you didn't actually
realize you'd got one or he just took a
phone was it a phone well you know what
it was we were in a business meeting cuz
we lost a load of money the manager s
calls up and
goes stop your blubbering get it
together girl get it together um and she
said anyway Bast telegraph's called up
you're going a Mitchell in store I said
that's no good anyway cuz we we have to
shut down cuz we're losing money and
then we devised a plan to to uh to take
advantage of the Michelin store yeah
yeah so what do you put you put almonds
in the bottom I put some ground almonds
in the bottom to soak up a little bit of
of the the liquid that come come out of
the pears you know that's kind of an old
French past project trip you know I've
never seen some sugar in here I'll put
it in there Chief you've got sugar in
there Su in yeah any lemon juice in
there just just sugar at the
yeah with pear no with with with fruit
in general you know we tend to think
that you know fruit is fruit a and that
we don't need to be too careful with it
but but fruit is an ingredient so we
need to be playing with things like the
acidity and the sweetness and the
ripness quite a lot if you're going to
be a good pastry chef you should treat
it the same way as we treat sauces so
you're seasoning the pears with lemon
juice yes because pears tend to be
really quite sweet you know um I once
had a PE
Tartan in in Marco's restaurant he sent
it out complimentary and actually it was
it was wasn't great because there wasn't
enough acid in it was all too sweet yeah
um pears need a bit of acidity which is
why the raspberries are nice and the
lemon juice is nice so you got lemon
juice in there I'm going to take the SI
because I'm going to pass the the yeah
please the rasp is in there as well so
your Pairs and you use this as a little
bit should I whisk the bowl or
you I'm going to leave you to do the
crumble the crumb's done it's waiting
for the pears right okay these pairs are
done now I am loving this I loving this
like nothing I'm sitting back in a of
you remember we used we used to cook
things like crumbles and sponges and
tartans quite a lot on steady cook
because only had 20 minutes we could get
it done quickly you know it's like it
wasn't if you made a pastry you had to
bring it all together and then roll it
out
and then get it on neatly Etc was you
did a crumble
it that on what people didn't realize
you do you do that I mean I used to go
back to the restaurant You' You' you'd
finish filming at sort of 5 or six o' do
service and then you'd be back in for
service that night you would be you'd be
you be backed in service un often CU we
had the hotel we go I'd do breakfast in
the
morning then go up to filming film two
shoot two shows and then you you'd go
back into the restaurant again but
phenomenal cuz these these guys used to
go out clubing that's I I never went to
a clubbing in my life master and servant
you see this what is we went to much
more they come eat your restaurant you'd
have to cook for him
that's okay um I think in the recipe
that I sent you you said you can put in
a bit of flour but nowadays I tend to
use the sort of Yankee thing where you
put in a bit of corn flour just to hold
the juices together because there's
quite a lot of juices in this now here
you want lemon in the cream little bit
of sugar and you you put the raspberry
through I don't put the the lemon in yet
whip the cream first please the lemon
goes in the wee bit near the
end huh
go so tell me tell me what you're up to
now then because you're you're about to
open somewhere else tell tell me about
this then ah yes two things to celebrate
first of all a new e and the second a
lifetime achievement reward yeah which
one one do you want to hear about first
Let's do let's do the let's do the new e
then go on so I'm doing a uh a food
offering with my brother at a local
Bowling Club it's called the Belmont
bowling club right and it's like it's
like Bast Wimbledon and we're going to
do nice sort of beastro almost Diner
type food for the members and things cuz
my brother wants to take a look at a
certain concept so I'm going to help him
with that um is your brother from a
Hospitality background no he's not which
is uh is he the
bowler we're both getting to a certain
age
now you see how that's come together
almost like a cookie bough yeah yeah
well I kind of crush it like that and
then I just break it up because I don't
like those sort of Sandy type crumbles I
like a crumble where it's almost bisc
and it's the butter that does that is on
top well it's sort of yeah it's
definitely the butter and the sugar
plays a huge part as well but it it's
taking it to this
this texture where where where it's
clumping if if if you work it too much
it's going to go over quite
quickly because you just want that sort
of softish yet firm so so you've got the
Bowling Club and another thing to this
lifetime achievement world what what
does that mean what I don't
know I did good I did better than I
thought it was you know
um who is it from it's from the
Tattler the the olster tler oh
theer you'll get the one from the tler
right I'll get one from the ster TPP
right um and I'm going to show you a
little cheats custard so tell me about
this custard then because this is this
is I'm looking at these ingredients
going what are you doing so can we turn
this on is it on it is on so I take sort
of tin custard or or prepared custard I
had equal amounts double cream and if
evaporated milk now this is a trick my
mom used to do she used to add
evaporated milk to her custard and we
used to think oh that is so exotic
that's
amazing did you do this at the Ros golf
no no you made it on glass no everything
was made
from I mean
yeah I mean a Lifetime Achievement Award
you know to run a michellin star
restaurant for 10 years you know that's
like a lifetime achievement in itself it
takes so much out of you so right so
what have you got in there then what
some vanilla extract you said you bring
it to the boil uh yeah or whack it in
the microwave or whatever yeah right so
we have an already one yeah yeah crumble
you know what we didn't do we didn't
choose a plate but you chose these
plates for me James is that right yeah
it's that looks that looks pretty good I
mean pairs a right pair is a truly
gorgeous
thing yeah why did you hide it in
there so how long you you cooked that
for oh it takes well it depends what the
size of the container is but about 30
minutes that's a I would let that cool
down
normally this it's good edges are nucle
you I forgot to put the ground almonds
when I made this one see that memor is
just going you know so the one that we
got in the oven that we got wait half an
hour one is the correct
one but it doesn't make any differ well
I mean well it does a bit doesn't it
well a little bit that this spin will be
nice and hot now so it means I'll be to
get a nice Canal out of
this slightly messy
one
right love
that taste it first James
any good it's a cheats one it is a
cheats one should we put some on yeah
Ladle James Martin doesn't do
ladles you this one needs a little bit
of corn FL or something to thicken it up
but I mean that's the sort of thing that
people will use at home so give us the
name of this pear crumble with a
raspberry cream and cheats custard
that's what it is Mr Paul ranking
everybody right there we go look at you
you like a kid 11 years old 11 years old
taking me back been a soldier things
like crumble like this yeah we doo in
the blackmist you always have a crumble
on yeah all the time yeah there's a big
spoon for you big spoon um can you tell
whether it's missing the
almonds it's it's got almonds on the
top crumbles proper when you yeah it's
delicious when you cook the apples and
the pears thoroughly in the crumble
that's what I love I don't like this
deconstructed reconstructed no I don't
either tast in it go everybody
this chap over here will'll be
showcasing his skills in the kitchen a
little bit later I'll be samping the
world famous cheese in another one of my
Spanish Adventures but join us again
after the break we'll be chatting to
comedian Lee Francis over a play that
hadock fish cakes but before you go this
is a little bit of childhood memories
for you all right so I don't this is the
first time I've ever done this come
on let's get here what's this 11y old
kid there we have all the after the
break
welcome back now make sure you don't
miss this week's little MK class in
place and gons that's coming up for you
very shortly and I'll be making a dish
of hey roasted chicken for s cleever in
just a bit but first i'm looking forward
to this I'm here with a comedian behind
some of the best of characters and some
of the funniest shows that have been on
TV the last 20 odd years it's the
brilliant Lee Francis
ching ching ching welcome to the house
CH Ching welcome to the house oh thank
you do you know what when I come to
people's houses I always feel guilty
because do I ask the question do I take
my shoes off do I do I do I leave them
on and wait for them to tell me to take
my shoes off so I've brought my own you
actually brought indoor house shoes I
brought these shoes these These are
really cool some Crocs um but an AR not
me cuz I do a lot of painting has drawn
my book cover it's I'm like an ego
Maniac look at me my
feet so tell me how it all started for
you then because this is you you've had
a fascinating career in terms of Comedy
wasn't wasn't what you wanted to get
into F wasn't what you want to get into
television what you want to get your
fashion was your your big love was it I
was a graphic designer um so I went to
art college for four years and whilst I
was doing that um I bought my friend's
video camera from him he couldn't afford
the payments his name is Keith Lemon and
he's a real person that I've known since
I was three
and so I bought his video camera and
started making silly videos um I did
quite well in the world of graphic
design I became senior artist of New
York Shing post um but in the back of my
mind I was like I I just want to be
messing about making silly films and
stuff and then U my then girlfriend
who's my wife now um she said you should
send your videos to TV well she didn't
she said Telly and um so I wrote a jiffy
bag on the Jiffy bag Telly and I got an
interview um on a show called watch this
space on um on channel four remember
like the T4 times yeah and I came
last but the producers liked me and
offered me a job at the Paramount
Channel where I wrote a sketch I'm
telling you everything so you don't have
to ask me anything no I'm I've I've been
doing research on you as well um and
then I wrote a sketch and did a video
every day whilst I was there because I
was an ideas person which also meant
making props in an office with none
other than Dom Jolly sat there Sasha
Baron Cohen sat there Simon Peg and
Jessica Hines over there over there was
no fielding and Julian Barrett and in
the corner there it was David Williams
and Matt Lucas he was famous for being
George doors then so I was like oh my
God there's um George dos there and I
gave him a script and a video every day
until they said we like this script
which was a script with deina Mcall
involved in it and said if you can get
her you can make that sketch she gave me
her agent's phone number she said are
you going to phone him I said no she
said do you want me to phone him I said
yes she phoned him and now I'm sat here
today that was a long story I hope you
didn't cut any you could dissolve cut it
cuz it really long one it and boring but
that was the story that's the that's the
whole story and it's in it's you've
condensed it in a book I've condensed it
into a book yes but what you you've only
got a look I mean your the pictures in
here really look what's tell us about
this What's um so that's the first Gizmo
I'm big fan of Gremlins um hopefully in
November I'm hosting something with Zach
gallagan who was Billy from Gremlins but
that's the first sure you're really into
this I mean you were into it when you
were young but you're really into it now
yeah yeah I still I still make mwise all
the time a kid always laughing at me go
how many gizmos are you going to make
that's my first Spider-Man suit I made I
think now I've got 22 Spider-Man
costumes and and tell tell me about
comedy because comedy's changed so so
much you you you speak to many comedians
they do the whole circuit you do the
working Men's Clubs you do the whole
thing yours was a different avenue but
also yours was a totally different look
at comedy you you characters was your
big thing nobody had really done it I
supp I don't know I there was you know
there was loads of character actors um
before I didn't invent doing characters
cuz of course Sasha Baron Co was Ali G
before um I I came on the scene but but
you were taking those characters and and
and they were sort of taking over your
life you know Keith Lemon people
genuinely must think you're Keith Lemon
well they do I'm forever saying now all
my name's leak when people go Keith can
I have a picture and I say oh my name's
Lee and do a picture and then they don't
believe my name's Lee or they laugh and
I go it's not funny Lee is not a funny
name if I was going to have some call
something funny I call myself gatus
gatus Francis
um but yeah they don't people don't
believe they don't understand that Keith
Lemon um was just a character as was
Avid Maran but I I live to those
characters and I thought it's easier
just to be them rather than tell you
about them was was that a a release side
for you when in terms of the comedy or
were they genuinely you thought well
I'll just try a bit of everything and
then something will something will my
then agent that deina McCall hooked me
up with saw me doing straight presenting
on a on on a show and he said I were
rubbish well he didn't say those words
at this time of morning I'll say it's in
the book what you what you really said
cuz I did read that b yeah cuz my my my
On's over there my my agent over here
she said I'll take you one as a trial 32
years ago right right 32 years ago yeah
yeah he said I was rubbish and he said I
prefer it when you do your characters I
used to review computer games in
character right and again I was I was in
my 20s I just did whatever he said yeah
let's do that then he went okay Lee
Francis is dead and and then um I have
to go into his office for a week doing
different characters I get changed to
the phone box outside his office right
like a really rubbish Superman um and
then convince him I was these people and
then we chose what characters we like
the best and then hit the Commissioners
even though the Commissioners didn't
know they were having a meeting with me
I just turned up and sabotaged the
meeting until Alan Parker the film
director complained about me at Aldo
zil's restaurant well I want to talk to
you about this because I I I remember
I remember seeing you no cuz I used to
go to Al Aldo used to do Ready Steady
cook and the restaurant used to be the
botom of Street in SoHo silly fish yeah
silly fish that long one yeah I I
remember did you see me in there do I
saw you in there I got who is this who
is this guy doing this but it's true
yeah well there one guy called Stuart
Murphy it was the commissioner of UK
play which became BBC 3 um one evening I
met up with him he didn't know he was
meeting me he was um convinced that I
was three different people and that
people that John was taking advantage of
and um and then then then John said to
him he said oh it's just one person and
then he says oh he can have his own show
and that's what happened but before that
I drew a picture of avid Mar and I drew
a picture of Keith Lemon and framed them
and put them up in the kitchen wall I
said to my wife one of these characters
will buy us a house that's manifesting
is it cuz she does a lot of manifesting
does my wife hello Jill don't know where
I'm looking uh um and I'm I'm bit Blas
about manifesting but it it seems to
work I'm here with you and I'm enjoying
it and I'm drinking fre booze on a
Saturday
morning so so tell me about the book
then because putting all that all these
stories on a bit of piece of paper a lot
of people get ghost writers and bits and
pieces you genuinely you I had a meeting
I had a meeting with a publisher right
well actually a lovely girl called
Georgie and and she said oh you should
do a book I said I want to do a book cuz
I'm I'm 50 now and I can still remember
how I got here yeah and I'm still
slightly relevant and she went I'll have
a word with my dad I went who is your
dad she was is the boss of Harper
Collins so I had a meeting with the boss
of Harper Collins I pitched a a
children's book called my dad's a ginger
werewolf which I wrote ages ago for me
kids H and I said or I want to do a
memoir and he kind of said um it's kind
of flooded with celebrities doing kids
books at the moment yeah he says but
we're interested in doing a memoir why
do you want to do it I said well cuz I'm
50 and I feel like that chapter of my
life what everyone knows me of that's
the end of that chapter and now I'm
going into a new chapter even though I
don't know what's going to
happen is that difficult for you cuz you
you spent your entire life in characters
and bit pieces or do you look at it and
go that's character it's not really
relevant anymore I don't want to do that
anymore you just that's that's that's a
moment in time and then I'm looking I
feel like it's a moment in time if was
on this and I feel like um it was quite
fashionable to to do characters and and
I don't know if it's that fashionable
cuz now it's the real you you know
you're Ching to this is is this the real
you yeah yeah I'm not I guess I'm not as
rude as Keith Lemon or as silly as Keith
Lemon but a lot of people think oh are
you shy in real life but I'm not I'm not
shy at all definitely definitely not shy
wasn't in the restaurant when I knew
that 25 definitely definitely you can't
be shy and do those sort of things I
guess although they do say a lot of
actors are quite quiet in real life I
guess they don't want to show off and go
look how great I am but anyway look we
got our sauce I've made the sauce using
some butter little B of flour uh I've
got water boiling up for a nice little
bit of um these are the the post that
I've done beforehand CU they keep really
well in ice cold water you don't need to
make them all in you can do them all in
advance as well these go in the fridge
you make these night before for
breakfast and easy as that just have
them in the fridge and they last for
three or four days in the fridge and
then the fish cakes I'm just going to
just slightly slightly have a pan fry in
a little bit of oil so you know when I
was at school um fish cakes were like um
a potato a fish there was not a lot of
fish in the ones that no but I did love
those and I've not had them since well
these made taste very no you look
amazing I'm not saying that they're
going be not as good as the school
ones there may not be to be honest with
you I remember at school having spam
fritters as well right spam fritters I
do remember spam the bad food are we
same age I'm I'm two years older than
you okay yeah well well we' eaten
similar bad food at school I guess
similar yeah very very similar spam FR I
can remember first time I had colaw at
school and I looking at going eating
that and then I had a little taste and I
loved it and then I went back to the
dinner ladies and just got a plate of it
like a Paramount mountain of colaw
chomping on that I thought it was the
food of the devil you see oh I loved it
as long as it didn't have raisins in I
can't stand raisins dirty pigs he do you
know what's funny though as well when I
was a kid the want for spinach because
of popey but we never had spinach in our
house never why not it's is it Posh I
don't know don't know it is Posh is it
spinach I spinach Posh didn't my mom
used to make a Sunday dinner s on top of
a
pancake on bizarre my my mom's a
beautiful wonderful woman but a terrible
cook right yeah Sunday roast on a
pancake I've never had that to be honest
with you I don't everyone time I tell
anyone the go don't know what you're
talking about I just do remember I'm
just thinking about all those times I
think I saw you saw be three or four
times in Al Alo zil restaurant really
yeah but did I annoy you no he didn't
annoy me I think he closed shortly after
that as well didn't he I used to have a
handheld karaoke machine which I would
sing when will I be famous to people in
the restaurant and they just look at me
like to polite well not politely but say
go away Well you certainly embarrass me
because I remember coming on the show
which I'll just finish off you're
celebrity juice I did celebrity juice
and uh you had me eating stuff out of a
sock and you had to describe what was in
the said sock without knowing what was
in the sock did you win a point for your
team was it worth it I did win a point
thank you so much for being a good spot
when you came on the thing things people
would do for a point for their te it was
just it was one of the most surreal
things were you on Holly's team I was on
Holly's team Holly's very competitive
she always wanted to win she did exactly
that look anyway we've got our nice
little bit of fish cake that we're going
to lift out hopefully this in fact I'll
put the spinach on it first so we'll put
the spinach on the plate it's not like
when you were at school no it's
definitely not but we'll put the spinach
on the plate we'll put the this on the
top oh so it's not likeing breadcrumbs
no breadcrumbs just can't fry this one
yeah how does it all stay together magic
magic yes with wish wishes and then look
you got the poached egg lovely she GNA
sit on the
top like that and then the
sauce we'll just take the sauce did you
always dream of being a chef then or did
always wanted to be a chef and even
after coming your show I still wanted to
be a
chef that sock inant didn't put me off
food for life I would never have been a
guest on Celebrity juice just because of
the food challenges that made me sick of
disgusting was fantastic and then we
have this thing called the money shot in
this
business there's your poached egg with
smoked haded fish cake and a nice little
mustard sauce done
right dive in oh great there we have it
tell me what you
think whether it whether it's the good
as the school
one wow no that beautiful nice it I I
love the egg as well egg poached egg
yeah I love eggs there you go you got
more if you want it there we go right
we're making boost you with proper
dumplings Philly later on the show we
join a spot a pastor from Chef John
hooker in just a bit but joins again
after break we're leaving Hampshire
behind and hitting the road on another
one of my food Adventures see you in a
bit good that a it yeah it's
good welcome back now Chef John hooker
will be taking over the kitchen later on
this morning and I've got a Mas glass in
place gons with a Tata sauce that's
coming your way very shortly but before
all that it's time to hit the road on
another one of my favorite food
Adventures this week I'm heading to a
farm near too in Spain to discover the
secrets of the world renowned Mano
cheese enjoy this
one I've been exploring the Magnificent
region of Castilla lancha home to the
historic former capital of Spain
too now excuse me if I take one more
final glance of this glorious
City I'm just heading out of the city
now to still in the same area to see how
this particular cheese is made and when
you think about the UK we have chedda in
France they have compte there probably
Spain's most famous cheese originates
and comes from these parts and that's
Mano like French champagne Mana has a
protected designation of origin meaning
it has to be made in L
mancha I'm visiting La Pruden Siana Farm
home to arti keso a big local cheese
producer who specializes in
Mano this delicious cheese can only be
made with the milk of Mana sheep and
here they have approximately 1,600 of
them the farm Works closely with the
factory where the milk is turned into
cheese it's run by the Alvarez family
and I'm meeting father Alfonso and Son
Santiago to find out how they make
it so here we are the start of the
factory yes here is the Mana she milk
okay and this is the sheep milk at 6:00
in the morning the cheese maker comes
and start filling the the tanks wow so
when once you start with the milk and
it's it it's put into to the Vats you
add the renit yes as the furthest sheep
farm is less than 20 km away they can
make the cheese here with raw milk so
there's no need to pasteurize it it's
pumped into Vats where it's heated and
in 1 hour 45 minutes that milk start
getting solid then it's passed through a
big mixing machine until the curds and
whe are ready to be
separated so you take the cheese the
liquid the liquid goes and we put it on
the trees because they way have a lot of
protein well it's very good for the
trees cuz they look fantastic outside
yeah it's very good next the cheese is
poured into a mold transferred into a
salt bath and left to set for 24
hours the 600 cheese in there 600 of
those in one
batch you're probably wondering what's
like some Roman bath but over here the
reason for this is it presses it cheese
down otherwise would just
float
wow look at that this is great to see it
like this because when you feel it it's
kind of like a it's like a soft bre it's
a it's a fresh cheese yeah
wow once the cheese is set the wheels
are transferred into aging rooms where
they're left to
mature this is the bit I've been looking
forward
to just check this
out there are literally thousands
thousands how many you have in here we
don't know you don't know just thousands
of them so what's the difference between
a semic cure cheese and a cure cheese
The semic Cure cheese spend the 3 four
month and when if have more months this
The
Cure the longer the cheese matures the
stronger the flavor and Santiago wants
me to try
some okay now we taste I'm looking
forward to
this this is a mild Mana a from 3 to 4
months it's quite interesting while he's
chopping that up is that I can see the
oldfashioned Press particularly the
wooden boards that the cheese would sit
on but
also the little band that you sort of
wrap it with to get that familiar sort
of pattern with it as well right so this
is the semic cured semic
cured it's beautiful I do love Mano I
really do whether you have it with just
hamon which is just beautiful
next is a mano the mature in extra
virgin olive oil for 10 to 12
months that's special huh you can taste
the olive you describe you can taste the
olive oil but it's much more rounded
it's like fine wine the old it gets in
the bottle the the the barrel the better
it gets
but this is the same
yeah you almost don't want to cook with
this you just want to just eat it as it
is you know you don't do anything with
it you know this you can play around
with it but this is just this is too
good you just eat it as it is and it's
wow this is
wonderful it's an amazing place that
incredibly hot but an amazing place now
Chef John hooker will be firing up the
Hobs forers later on this morning and
I'll be sharing some recipes for gons in
this week's mask class that's all coming
up in just a bit but I'll see you back
here in a few minutes when I'll be
serving up a dish of roast chicken in
hay for Sue cleav from Coronation Street
see you in a
bit welcome back now Chef John hooker
will be treating us to a cracking pasta
dish very shortly and I'll be showing
you how to make gons with some amazing
seasonal place in this week's little
Mass that's coming up next but first
swapping the cobbles away Le field for a
seat at my kitchen is an award-winning
actress who's been playing the part of
alen Grimshaw in Cory for nearly 25
years it's a brilliant s Cleaver
a welcome welcome to the show my my
family are going to be super excited now
oh bless that's very kind of you it's
super exciting now I know you're a big
food lover as well so I thought I
thought with this i' thought you'd do a
classic roast chicken nice roast chicken
with a differ so we're going to cook it
with hay right so hay you you this is
Pet Shop hay don't get it from the the
rabbit hutch otherwise those little bits
of raisins tanas are not very good in
here but you just got look you just got
your standard Pet Shop hay and then I've
got some chicken and all you really do
with that is
just that what I'm going to do is use
some of this this is a bit of lavender
and use the cooking lavender really so
when you're going around the garden
center there's lavender used for soap
and medicinal stuff and then you get the
cooking one there's loads of different
varieties but that's that one that I'm
going to pop in here so I can't just go
in my garden and pick my lavender I
don't know what lavender you've got but
that's because there's going to be sort
of How It's grown and all yes I just
take it take just use a little bit of it
if it tastes of soap then don't use it
again right so is the flavor different
then yeah lav all the lavender is
different you get tons of different sort
of flavored lavenders some more fragrant
the other so if you were going to if you
wanted to grow lavender for for culinary
purp cooking lavend you get the cooking
ones that you're I seen it at the Garden
Center the other day by the by the herb
section and bits of pieces I've seen
seen it there so salt and pepper over
the top little bit of oil
and then what I do just just I tie the
little legs stop and falling apart ready
so and I'm really glad you've not let me
down on the amount of butter you're
using well this is just a start of it so
we haven't started yet I'm going to use
that entire pack as well and we've used
the other pack in the mashed potato
that's been res served with it as well
uh but first of all I want to talk about
yourself really because we're going to
get on the book in a minute but but
acting wasn't in your blood really was
when you were younger was it or no it
kind of you kind of fell into it wasn't
it but you traveled a lot as a young kid
yeah well traveled a lot as a young kid
not not not so much I mean holidays with
the family uh you know just but you
ended up in Canada didn't you you ended
up well no that was when I was uh that
was when I was 18 I went off as a nanny
I had uh talk about in the book my
childhood was in Scotland so uh we lived
in Scotland at my father taught at
gordonston so I had this great sort of
childhood just running free when no one
was in the school you I had a moped at
10: and just you know it was just great
you know you go out in the morning and
then just make sure home when the Sun
goes down but don't go near the lake but
I don't remember ever being told off and
I don't there wasn't too much worry
about you know if you drowned or not in
those days you just you just got on with
it didn't you you just and so tell me
about didn't you get into the acting
side of it through you got invited for a
friend of yours invited you to a play
was it yeah when I was a a nanny in
Canada I was must have been 18 19 my
friend was joined an amateur Dramatics
group and she said oh you come and see
me in this play I went yeah of course I
will so off I went and I watched her and
I sat there and I thought oh this is
awful now I mean I did think that but I
mean I feel terrible saying it but I
just looked and I went oh my Lord she is
shocking that's shocking did you tell
her this no I did all that oh well done
you and I just thought but why is she
doing that [ __ ] and I just went that's
what I'm going to do and I literally
rang having never mentioned it or
talking about to anybody in my life I
rang my mom and went hey Mom I'm coming
home I'm GNA go to drama school and be
an actor and then I came home I I did I
went to drama school I got in at drama
school and then I was asked to be in a
just like a small a couple of the
students were asked to go and be in I
think there was four of us asked to go
and be in a play at the Royal exchange
theater um edus yeah and off we went and
on the first day of being there uh there
was an actor in the show called Michael
en Harbor
who looked at I think it went up to Dave
throl and said she is the absolute
double of my wife when I met her and to
cut a really long story short his wife
turned out to be my birth mother I have
two half sisters also in the business
the whole family were in the business
Kate my sister is Wendy and Bob the
Builder and Sean the Sheep and animation
she spent their life you know sounding
like various animals and creatures uh in
animation so yeah that that it was it
was in the blood and you say about this
because you WR you you've written a book
you say it's not an autobiography but
you look at your your life as well
as comparing with the other people's
lives as well it's no so what it is i'
I've written a book um it's called a
work in progress it's it's it's for
women of a certain age you know I'm 61
now and you know I think a lot of women
once they the kids have grown up and we
get to that point of our life where
society would like to see a Shuffle off
and it's like we feel you can feel like
we're not that we're past our Prime that
we don't have a voice that we're not
relevant we filled with self-doubt and
this is a book to empower women of that
age so it's a it's a call to arms for
women of a certain age and I use the
first half of the book by telling my
stories and my backgrounds and I use my
stories to then in the second half of
the book show how to affect change in
your life in my own life and how you
hopefully can affect that change to live
fearlessly in your in your your older
years that's you on screen for for 20 20
odd years 25 years 25 years you don't
come across as you come across as very
confident but I get the feeling your
private life is your private life you
like to keep that separate that's I
think do you think I think that's always
the key to to doing this for longevity I
I do the same thing I think you've got
to have it's difficult to separate the
two but I think there's got to be two
don't you I mean I'm I'm stage now where
I I kind of I finally like myself and I
am confident in who I am and I don't
answer to anybody but for many many many
years I I found it excruciating I would
have this bront that everyone would see
nobody would know but inside I was
incredibly anxious full of self-doubt
and Loathing so this this was the time
that I wanted to share what helped what
changed how I feel that I've changed in
my life what's helped me and and in the
hope that it will will help other women
because you know no matter what we do
the circumstances we have you know the
roles the jobs we have pretty much all
of us as human beings are suffering with
the same problems in our inner world you
know those moments of you know
insecurity and not being good enough and
being I'm thinking of this with this
Source am I getting this right but this
is this is in here so we've got the shot
I won't judge you for it no this is the
shots and the garlic that gone in here
I've Cris up my little bit of over here
I've got my mushrooms over here the the
the chicken quite simply just gets
roasted like you would do with a normal
chicken like this and then we just take
it out would you only use wild mushrooms
for this no you can use any mushrooms to
be honest so it's wild mushrooms are
great cuz this time of the year um and
we want to showcase that really as chefs
we just like to say these are amazing
look out for them they are around all
over this country as well these depends
on where you live of course but and can
I check something because you've used
just hay from the pet shop yeah so the
juices that would have come out of that
I know the hay will absorb it but you
couldn't then use some of the pan juices
no you you'd have to put it on a trivet
if you want to do that but you don't
really need it for this because the the
key to this is all about the the sauce
so then you can start deglazing it with
a little bit of this is that
the the noily whats it yes that's I've
been to this marcian Haven they I've
been to that and then you allow that to
reduce a little bit and then you use
this stock cuz if you put this stock in
it makes a sauce instantly wow so
usually with stock you've got to reduce
it to get the flavor this one you can
turn up the heat and almost get a sauce
straight away with a touch of the
mustard and some cream and that kind of
stuff but I want to talk to you about
what you've done away from sort of Cory
Coronation Street as we or Cory as we
call it in my house but CRA was another
thing you you must to to get on stage
that must have been a great release from
you doing that really because when you
did it you didn't actually watch sister
before you were in it is that right no I
well I I I haven't been on stage for 25
years and then this year they came and
said would you like to do the national
tour of Sister Act and I thought well I
can either just out of you know being
scared and frightened and all those say
no or I can just embrace it and I went
yeah I'll do that you know I want to do
going forward I'm just doing things that
really interest me and I find fun I've
done the I me my son's grown up I've
been I've done all my all all my
beautiful roles and I've enjoyed being a
mother but I very much have chosen that
this decade is for me and it yeah and it
started with you know when I got asked
to go in the jungle that the question I
you know I immediately went no no no no
no no and then I thought why am I saying
no and the only reason I could think of
was that I was scared and you know I've
talk in the book about one of my biggest
fears about going to the Jungle had
phobia about snakes can't touch a
couldn't touch a snake on the page and
then I really thought about and thought
how many times have I actually come face
to face with the snake where it's
wrapped itself around me it's taken a
chunk out of me never in my life so I
realized I just thought I was frightened
the snakes and as I got there and I
found out that you know I wouldn't share
a room with the snake I wouldn't invite
one over fatigue but you know I'm
actually I don't have a phobia I just
thought I did so and that's what I've
that's how I've been living since then
I'm just whatever comes up I'm not going
to say no because I'm unsure or scared
I'm just going to say yeah and see where
it takes me well see where it goes well
I'm just going to finish off recapping
what we got over here there we have your
lovely mashed potato this is the other
part of the butter that you didn't see
going this is the butter and the cream
in this mashed potato over here how much
how many potatoes are in there
two what pack of butter two potatoes
yeah pack of butter and and a and a bit
of cream a lot of cream it's going to go
in there and then the sauce gets reduced
down but the key to this sauce is you
use a tiny little bit whenever you got
anything with bacon and mushrooms bacon
acrosses the fat which is lovely because
the sauce is going to go in the last
minute so that that's bacon goes in here
and the mushrooms go in what I like to
do with either bacon or mushrooms
anything like that you add a tiny bit of
cherry vinegar at the end and it just
lifts it all up but what we're going to
do is take our mashed potato beautiful
like that so with that that hay will
that have flavored that at all hopefully
you're about to find out but you got
little bit bit of the oh you see and
I've got the leg Yeah little bit of the
thigh little bit of the chicken breast
over here like that and we got the sauce
the sauce will freeze really well and
you take this lovely mushrooms and the
bacon so pretty and the sauce over the
top so automnal so there we have
it good Lu with the book and good luck
eating that my classic roast chicken
cooked in hay with a simple little W
mushroom sauce done
woo right dive into that thank you there
you go tell me the starter your your
main course is going to be uh beef stew
and dumpling St this is the little
little starter so you think everything
on there the chicken yeah chicken with
the little bit of shin in there but oh
that's so nice it's delicious isn't it
right I'll be serving up a final course
of Beast and dumplings for Sue and Lee a
little bit later and we've got more
cooking on the way from John hooker very
shortly but John again after the break
we'll be giving you a stepbystep guide
in making gons using some place that's
banging season right now and I'm going
be serving it with a simple little TARTA
sauce that you make yourself see you
after the break
welcome back now we're treating Lee
Francis and my guest Sue cleever to a
proper beef stew and dumplings at the
end of the show but first it's time for
this week's masas and this week's mascas
I thought I'd teach you how to cook and
prepare a brilliant bit of place in one
of my favorite dishes really this is
really a chef's favorite dish gons and
know they say it's really simple but it
is really really simple it's Classic
this particularly when You' got fish as
good as this this has come from the West
country it's come line CAU usually these
these are all beautiful I've actually
caught these myself not this size
slightly smaller off sort of the needles
area really on sandbanks like that but
this time of the year they're absolutely
superb and I wanted to show you this
because I use these in the restaurant
even yesterday I was cooking with it in
the restaurant now how do you face it
how do you prepare something like this
well the first thing is is you remove
what we call the fins or the skirt so
this is the classic called the little
skirt or the fin you just cut these with
a pair of scissors all the way around
here now the same process applies
whatever flatfish you're preparing so
you always really start off like this
the classic bin dova Soul DOA sing yeah
that that sort of fish that's cooked on
the bone we remove these off prior to
cooking it whole so just trim these off
like this just makes it easier to fill
it but what's quite interesting when you
do stuff like like this you actually see
it the fets how they actually sit how
they actually are and then when you do
order something on the bone which is the
best way to do it if you are going to
cook fish like this on the bone it's the
best way to actually eat it in the
restaurant you then know where the bones
are so Nature's been amazing it's
actually drawn a line all the way down
here cuz there's four filets on a
flatfish two on a round fish four either
side so you got one there one there and
then on the other side turn this over
you got one there now ever so slightly
you can see this line appear on the
other side as well so this is where your
knife Cuts one that side and one that
side so it will turn that around and you
follow the knife along that line now
it's depends on which knife you want to
use really this is classed as a sort of
a A Classic fiting knife you can see the
blade bends this is a boning knife this
is used predominantly for meat but I
still use this to fill it fish with you
can use either or really but you follow
this line so get it exactly on there and
the KN will go all the way down till it
won't go any further down to the bone so
if I do this you'll make the
noise you can hear it just hit that bone
now then what you do is you make sure
you do this in
long I'll change the knife now I'm using
the filet knife cuz the filet knife
bends like this this is what you want to
do is push it down and as you're fiting
it like this and pushing it along it
follows the edge of the bone but when we
put the knife in you start with long
cuts so the knife goes in you make these
long incisions so rather than do it sort
of small incisions when you put the
knife in you make these long cuts you're
pressing the knife all the way down to
the
fillet to the Bone right the way down
all the way down like that and then as
we go this goes all the way down and you
start trimming off this entire fillet
like this now you'll always have either
a long fillet which is that and you'll
have a short fillet on this side and the
same the other side like I said four
fillets and the idea is to get as much
meat on the fillet and none on the bone
like that you see the Bone's nice and
clean which is what you want and do
repeat the process the other side so
I'll just leave that to one side because
I'm going to
concentrate on this one and make these
gons so to do this now we can then trim
this little bit off
here trim that off it's entirely up to
you whether you leave this on or trim it
off but we trim that off and then you're
left with a beautiful bit of fish now I
actually leave the skin on I think it's
a northern thing I don't know some
people like it some people don't I love
the skin on fish it's up to you so I'm
going to go how I used to love it when I
was a kid and we're going to take our
gons and thinly slice the fish so slice
it all the way through you want to make
sure that this is not too thick the
whole idea of gons is they just cook
quite quickly so slice it all through
like
that now it depends what you want to do
with in terms of fish you can do this
with Cod you can do it with hadock you
can do it with place it's entirely up to
you but this is just beautiful you get
these long pieces like that and you can
just repeat the process now when you get
fish this good as well don't be
frightened to buy it fresh prepare it
and freeze it as well because it freezes
nicely this so once you got the fish
like this
keep all the bones all the bits and
pieces all this you keep all this
because it makes the most wonderful
stock put it in cold water a little bit
of aromat and peppercorns a little bit
of celery onions bring it to the boil
you don't waste any of it cook it for
about 20 minutes fish stock because
otherwise it starts to go a little bit
bitter and then what you can do is
freeze that and then you can use it for
wherever you want as well soup and bits
of pieces it's delicious so to make our
little gons we've got a combination over
here just quickly wash my hands we've
got a combination of flour egg and bread
crumbs now this is called tapan that's
what the meaning is it means you
basically flour it first then in egg and
then in bread crumb so what you need to
do first of all is season the flour so
salt and
pepper this is the seasoning bit rather
than season the
fish and you can pop the
fish straight into here like that then
we get some
egg a little bit of egg like
that and then we want some beaten egg
do that quick
mix then we grab the fish roll it in the
flour like that this is just plain flour
then you pop it into the egg so just get
rid of any excess
flour off of here we go that tray can
then
go then you bring this one
up with this one so so roll it around in
the egg like that flour egg and bread
crumbs it's just one of the classic
combinations when you get place this
good like I said all fish is seasonal
but this time of year it's so good at
the moment is the place we get
in so that can then sit in the
breadcrumbs now these are panco
breadcrumbs which are basically dried
and shaved they produce a much crispier
crumb you can just use normal white
sliced bread but the best advice really
is I would probably dry out not toast it
but just dry out a low oven so once
you've got that we've got our lovely
crumb on our
fish like this you can just pop it back
on
here like I said this once you've done
this you can then freeze it and if you
are freezing it the best off to do it is
freeze it on a tray first rather than a
bag otherwise it all just goes to one
lump and then when it's frozen transfer
it into a bag rather than just freeze it
into a bag so that's that one so quickly
wash my hands
again and then the fryer I've set quite
hot because these aren't going to take
very long at all so I'm just going to
leave those to one second which what we
are going to do now is concentrate on
the little garnish for this and this is
a simple little TARTA sauce now to make
your own tart sauce is way better than
it is buying it miles better than using
B in mayonnaise as well this is so so
easy I'm going to show you it now so the
the gons are only going to take well 30
seconds a minute maybe something like
that so you take the eggs first of
all like
that egg yolks you can use whole eggs
for mayonnaise but I just
use little bit of egg yolks and then
what we're going to do is add some
mustard always de your mustard for this
never English mustard it's a bit strong
that goes in there and then fire this up
first of all get that going while
happening we're just going to check on
our fryer turn it up a little bit pretty
good and what you want to do is emulsify
this together now you can add a touch of
vinegar to start off with but what I'm
going to do is just add that towards the
end because you add the oil gently and
it starts to mulfy this together this is
just vegetable oil so you don't add
things like rape seed oil in mayonnaise
no olive oil it's just vegetable oil now
if you want to change the recipe a
little bit and you like your salad cream
cream you actually make your own solid
cream it's done exactly the same way but
you use hardboiled egg yolks so you put
hardboiled egg yolks in here instead of
raw egg yolks mustard touch your vinegar
pour in the oil and you just finish that
with a little bit of lemon juice touch
your cream you've made your own solid
cream but gradually gradually we're
going to pour this in the Temptation is
to add this quicker if you add it
quicker sometimes the May a can split
and then you almost OS start again and
add the split liquid to a c more egg
yolk so just take your
time like that and it starts to thicken
people think you more add more oil it
gets thinner does the opposite and then
to bring that back to make it thinner
again now we add the touch of
vinegar just a little bit of
vinegar mix
together you've now got the your
own little mayonnaise we can then use
this base I've done so much times before
on the show as well in terms of adding
things like ketchup and you've got your
Merry rose sauce with a little bit of
Brandy that we're going to make a
classic Tata sauce now so for that we
want Capers girkins and shalot so this
is almost ready now so while I'm
preparing this these can go in so take
your simple little
gons like
this in the fryer
nice hot fryer bang straight
in going to want no more than about a
minute minute and a half meanwhile we
can pair a little
shalot so when you're adding shalots to
this and use shalots not onions they're
too strong so you add this chop shalot
get it nice and
thin a nice and small dice for this as
well so little bit of
shalot then you've got some girkin
going to go in there as well little bit
of
Capers all in and then you can take the
whole
lot straight into our
bowl with some herbs I've got some
parsley and a bit of Dill is the usual
ones in a nice little bit of Tata
sauce this is not far off now they don't
take very long at
all if you're cooking more than this do
them in batches of
course stops them oil sticking together
but make sure the oil is really really
hot CU you want the bread coms to Brown
and you want the fish to cook quite
quickly because the fish is nice and
thin they'll cook quite quickly so
pretty good they can come
out out of there look at
that touch your salt over the
top sits to one side and we're going to
finish this off now with uh
few bits of herbs it's purely optional
really Dill is the most prioritized one
really what you want to put in here so
dill and parsley I like to use for this
but stay clear sort of coriander and
that kind of stuff it's just
overpowering but they're The Usual
Suspects in a tart
sauce Touch of
that and then a little
squeeze of lemon
juice bit of on there as well and not
forgetting the salt and the
pepper and we're
there and it just showcases this amazing
fish to its best I think it really is
delicious but look at that simple little
T sauce bring this
over you got this look at
that so delicious so simple to make
yourself and you got these
gorgeous
fresh gons a place they really are
special when fish is this good as well
and you don't forget you can use the
entire look at that white that is in the
middle don't forget you can use the
entire lot of this fish as well you use
the bones the skin everything so nothing
gets
wasted and
then finally a little wedge
of lemon
to go with it just a little
touch of Water
Crest and there we have it a classic
classic dish using when it's in season
one of the best fish out there Place
gon's homemade Tata sauce
done they really doing that because they
want some uh now if there's anything you
like to learn about in a little Mast and
do get touch we see if we can help out
right here on the show now I'll be
serving up beach D and dumplings for all
my guests that's leaf assistant Sue
Cleaver in just a bit but join us again
after the break we're going be joining
more incredible cookery this time from
Chef John hooker see you after the
break welcome back now I'll be treating
my guests Lee Francis and Sue cleever to
a sh stopping beef stew and dumplings
I'm looking forward to that that's
coming at the end of the show but first
I'm here with Mr Paul Rankin we're about
to enjoy a dish from a
who saved two local PBS from ruin and
turned them into the pride of Deon it's
a brilliant Mr John
hooker great to have you back Chief and
you're going to be cooking for us what
are you going to be doing so we're going
to be doing we're going to be showcasing
some West country games today so as
we're banging the ainal season games
flying through the restaurant as we
speak so this dish is born out of really
using a allot of our trim and our waist
and turnning into dish so we're going to
make a ragu out of out of some pheasant
some Partridge yeah some of our vanice
and then we're going to put some fatty
pork belly for it as well just to give
it a bit of indulgence a bit of fat
going for cuz the meat is so lean and
then we're going to turn that into
raviolo raviol low yeah so singular
you're tell me out too tight probably I
you get more than one you get one you
get one it's a star you're going to be
doing star yeah so what are you you're
going to be doing if you could roll me
some pasta yeah I'll I'll go get on with
the Bas I'll get that so I'm looking at
this I'm going it's kind of like mince
yeah it's mince is it's like mint and
tities your mom us do there's nothing
wrong with that paol is there well when
I was up Sky I had mints and tities on
the menu yeah yeah um because I love it
I grew up with it and it sits a pub
mints and tities and I think like this
was you're ping it up though big yeah
we're ping up and also it's giving good
value and it's watching what we're doing
in this current climate to get value out
of our produce and what we're doing
using it
respectfully and yeah we have this on
throughout the year we always we always
have a pasta dish on at the pub whether
it's a toini or Ravioli and what's going
on in here what are you so I'm just
sealing off all of the the we've got
shot D shalots garlic and then we're
going to seal off all of the meat so
we've got the minced the minced pheasant
trim the minced
Partridge the Venison and the pork belly
and do you want this really thin or do
you want it yeah thin Jing go that would
make a good terine wouldn't it yeah
wouldn't it's a similar base You' use
for a t where you just put livers
through it and press it yeah yeah yeah
so so you got to we've got to mention
you're celebrating many many things at
your place really bib Gom on now yeah
bib G on for l seven
seven eight years but to keep that as
well but most you know the biggest thing
for you really is that this gastro pub
second second in second in the UK yeah
it blows my mind really wow
blows yeah it blows my mind we um we've
been in the list for 10 years and always
never never met broken into top 10 but
and again it's Testament to the
hardworking team they believe in what we
do they work really hard you know your
team's good but you know are they really
that good
yeah they are they are they are you know
your team butly about you yeah I suppose
but like it's a good
a it's modist as well yeah it's a great
bit of Kos and there's some there's some
very good operators that yeah and like
for us to be in and around that really
from when from our humble beginnings we
started off when em and I risked
everything to to get that Pub and and
operate a pub in our home town it kind
of like and again it puts Tav on the map
I suppose and yeah we're going to hit
this with some um tomato
puree some wer sauce for a really Savory
night and C that have you ever had an
Italian taste this love all l no I can't
say I have on might have had some
stealth Italian customers of eating it
but and again it's it's just our
interpretation of like a more of a
refined version of using the game yeah
and then we're going to use red white
wine in this as well your your
restaurant itself so the the Cornish
arms is in the center of Tav yes emmer
and I Emma and I moved in there 12 years
ago Liv there for 5 years and I suppose
the biggest compliment I give us in the
team is that we're cooking with our
appetites we're cooking food we like to
eat yeah that's the biggest thing I I I
what have you just thrown in there so
there's some some stock gone in there
some um chicken and beef stock bit of
gam sock and then some tomato Pata as
well or chopped tomato to a certain
extent I think that you know if you
think of yourself as a kind of serious
Chef you always have to cook the food
that makes you happy because that's what
makes it individual there's only one of
you in life you know yeah and I suppose
suppose it comes from that is I suppose
we're lucky enough that we've we've
driven that with two of you to be honest
with
you so then we're going to braze this
for 40 minutes at 180 okay so you're
doing that in the oven yeah I I I always
even though I do it at home for the kids
and stuff like we you make this at home
for the kids well out of beef not out a
game and then what you're left with is
beautiful bnes Ragu again it' be
beautiful with just some spaghetti or so
you used pork fat to give it moisture
pork Fat's going there as well yeah so
that's what that's what that's our
finished product so make sure when
you're brazing it you braze it right
down and reduce it CU we want it to be
quite thick to put into the rav okay
that's I think a lot of people are not
in Hospitality don't realize how many
good dishes comes out of oh I've got to
use that up I have to find a nice way to
to and all of a sudden something flowers
and you've got a new B yeah and it's
usually using the pits like we're saying
the pork belly and that kind of when you
got I always think bra beef cheeks and
stuff like that you got bra beef stew I
love when you got bra it properly I love
stuff we're just going to kiss the edges
of the pasta that you've kindly weighed
out for me with a bit of the edges of
the pasta yeah the sensual pasta we're
not we're not we're not
dring nurturing it that's what we're
doing he's trying to take your job I
know it's been trying since he first
came on all right you two are all
professionals I know about that but and
then we're going to build the
ravioli
so again it's key that we pinch that
edge
in get rid of all those air bubbles
because if we don't get rid of that air
it just explode when we when it hits so
folks that don't know at home
multiple of those is called ravioli yeah
and singular is ravo
raviolo and and then you get the other
crazy chefs do open ravioli where it's
not a
ravioli life it's just a piece of
bastard something there's one now would
you make freeze them really well do you
you can blanch them and freeze them yeah
yeah they're not quite the same when you
freeze them are they no you can't beat
fresh pasta I don't think at least a bit
of salt so they're cooking away nice
well the Italians are pretty good at the
frozen ravioli game the Frozen ra well I
mean the the commercial Frozen Ian pasta
can be very good so anyway that's
cooking away nicely what what else are
you doing now then going to go onto this
um the garnish and the base we're going
to let move that over there thank you
James so what we've done here is sweated
off some shalots just in some
butter and some salt and then we just
tied some time to um get that flavor of
time going through the shalots and this
is going to be our base that we're going
to sit the raviol on and again like as a
chef over the years we've always turned
everything into purees and I just kind
of want to come away from that a little
bit and keep that real savory beautiful
shot we've all got better teeth nowadays
so this is almost like a classic SES
would come out with some classic s
through but we're going to De glass that
with Sherry vinegar so you I mean we
know that he trained classically in
missing three missing St restaurants
what about you for training I just I
just found a really good my college
lecture at College just in instilled
into me classic French cookery guy
called Colin nson and that's where he
ignited a flaming me about cookery
really where did you end up working when
you were
um went to a place a big fishing gaming
shooting hotel called the irand alarms
had three rosettes at a time there was
20 chefs in the Brigade went in there's
a Comm I thought it's do or die so
either go and shine or jacket in and I
don't know what I would have done really
yeah but yeah and so it it came to Rish
I was there for a couple of years and
yeah and started off from there and
again I've learned a lot of stuff about
good produce when I was there so in
these chots well put malt
extracts so from malt barley and again
it's going to give that real sweet note
to it but it's not it's probably got
half the sweetness of refined normal
sugar right so it's going to give off
that really rounded Savory note but this
is the interesting thing with your food
cuz you got you've got classic classic
stuff as well as modern techniques you
yeah yeah it's driven by the team and we
are layering up flavors with punches of
acidity CU our food is very rich and we
need that acidity to give you a little
bit of Light Relief when you're also the
texture gives you Tex texture gives you
a relief from uh richness too I think
yeah yeah you don't want it to be
onedimensional no not all I'll tell you
a story when I when I was working at the
gabros I was telling my dad we had this
dish on at Christmas time it was a
mousse of grous served with a brussel
throat puree a chestnut puree and a
white onion puree I'm serve with a bit
of je and my dad looks at me and says is
that for it's that is that for the
people who have no
teeth I know we've all been guilty of it
as Chef we've always gone and pureed
everything and
trying in theory it's refined but I
don't enjoy that type of food anymore no
and I think as you get as you find your
own style and your palette refines a bit
then you kind of like you come away from
all that and it's just yeah style over
substance no CU a flavor but there is a
place for it yeah you know so what do
you got here then so we' just got some
pickle walnuts here that we're you love
these black walnuts I remember having it
with s cabbage when I was there chop
yeah with a pork chop we do it with um
we make a mayonnaise out of it and it
takes tastes like salad cream real salad
cream Vibes to it and we dress a roasted
hisy cabbage of it yeah where did pickle
walnuts come from um I we use them yeah
did they come from the continent or
they're English they're English are they
English are they the so here we've got a
bit of game sauce which we're going to
just so that's used from the bones that
you've got the bones we've roasted off
yeah and we've put some brown chicken
stock with that as well we've made a
little game you and then we go to PL you
know
James there go well I'm looking forward
to this place it so with the rav with
the raviola we're just going to dress
them with a bit of olive
oil and what we've got here is some bait
parmesan just Parmesan I mean you can do
this in the microwave as well actually
it comes out really well in the
microwave just put it on a baking tray
and bake it in discs and how do you bake
it in just on have you got a mold yeah
just do it in a mold oh you just do it
through the mold thinking the people at
home will be going how you do that
cooked you can after yeah eat the bits
and then what we've got here is some
toasted yeast flakes which we toast
toasted yeast flakes like nutritional
yeast they're really Savory try
that you had those before that's all
right that's all right that a it which
again it's it's we're layering up
flavors textures like a ve a vegetarian
crack yeah is that yeah it's really good
and that's just literally toast in
butter yeah and we're going to we're
going to split that sauce out almost
like a V
God in the old days and Ready Steady
cook we used to get people writing in I
I like when Chef's cooking but I don't
like it when they put all the oil
on but and again that I know you're
banging on about flavor profiles and
layering flavors that that olive oil
gives a real nice pepperiness okay and a
bit of mouth Pei too yeah and then what
we're going to do with this is a load of
age
parmesan on top of it as well yeah
wef what other French words do you know
just wef
that's what I
thought my son actually my son right my
son last night I tell you story my son
last night was like he's cting to me in
10 in French night I got to about six I
think yeah I epic fail and there it goes
there's the
rav looks looks great doesn't it so it
looks really quite simple in
presentation but there's layers of
detail
underneath huge amount of work so so
give us the name of this dish it's
raviol West country game good man and
yeah there you go Mr John hooker
everybody thank very
much C that nice job man nice
job right so you got dive into this
thank you I'm really look get one each
this is very luxury you you tell me off
El well it's
luxury so I know he going you just have
to make a mess of it to get yeah you
just got to get you just got to get
stuck in just going to dive in get stuck
in wow that's a tasty biter
H delicious isn't that fantastic
ah really really
delicious you got some Talent there I
tell you it really really really is but
there you go John hooker everybody thank
you that is fantastic right we've got
time for one more final course so join
us again after the break where we're
laying on lunch for both of my guests
Sue cever and Le Francis and these two
I'll see you in a few minutes that is
delicious welcome back now to the last
part of the show
sadly but I'm back in the kitchen with
John Paul Le and
sue you today would be a good show uh
right we're going to fire it off we're
going to finish off the show in style
this Michin star chefs big gum on Chefs
everything else we're going to do beef
stew and
dumplings wrong with that beef stew and
beef stew and dumplings so I've got some
beautiful beef over here we're going to
use the Chuck but we got we're going to
seal this off we dust it with a is Chuck
your go-to then for a bit to me really
but what is my go-to is I don't buy it
from a supermarket because I get the
meat from a Butch is I thought you going
to say just wrestle with a
wild have you seen her
outside there's one L you know when you
say Chuck I mean that sounds to me quite
an American Chuck is that is that the
same as brazing steak or what is it yes
but when you yeah if you get brazing
steak but you want a piece H and the
pieces usually cost a little bit less
than the portion it all up into dice so
that's the only difference if I go in
and say I want a Chuck a joint of Chuck
joint of Chuck yeah and you'll get
you'll go home and cut it like this with
brazing steak there could be any amount
of cuts that that they put in it and
they'll all cook a different time yeah
do the do the onions for me oh really
yeah yeah yeah yeah it can be it can be
anything like they'll cook at different
times you won't get such a consistent
result from different parts of the yeah
they'll just all whack it into brazing
steak you know that you do a lot of
cooking so I do abely yeah this this
what you want the key to this though to
is is the Browning of it that's the most
important bit so a little bit of flour
the flour doesn't necessarily help it
brown but what the flour will do is
thicken the stew so once you this is the
bit that's going to thicken the stew we
add no flour to it afterwards it's this
in the right of stock and the amount of
time that it takes to cook that's the
key to it so I'm going to text you about
your book first of all because you both
sort of both of you we've got both we
match look at the color match we do
match autobiography you say this is not
an autobiography but it isn't it's kind
of stories the first half stories of my
life second half it's kind of a Call to
Arms Manifesto for women of a certain
age would would you ever write an
autobiography cuz I
think tell the truth well I mean there
there is a lot about me in the first
half yes there is a lot about me um she
met Peter a all yeah I did told me a
wonderful story about that's in the book
that's exciting book yeah yeah but um
yeah I mean to be honest I never
imagined writing a book but the process
of it I've absolutely loved and I I
think I might I've got a couple of other
things that I'm thinking about doing so
yeah but also I mean doing stuff like
you you're both playing characters in
theory you play characters but your you
know people know you must the amount of
people on the street that know you from
the character not the real you because
you've you've also been quite private in
your so so writing a book for you must
have been do I put that in do I do I not
put it in yeah I mean that was hard for
me because I you know in the book like I
said I've always kind of hidden from
putting Sue out there people have only
ever seen the character I play and I
purposely I kept my life very private
you know I wanted to bring up my son I
didn't want the intrusion in his life
and so yeah so it's been very it's very
strange for me to just be out there and
and and revealing all the jungle quite
up you that's very revealing isn't it
and I mean that was that that was a a
great experience and we all I mean we
did have a great I did have a really
good time there there we all did and
we're all still in touch which is really
nice but the difficult I suppose for
that is the control you have no I mean
you you don't have control when you go
on this show but no let but you have you
have no control over that do but at
least you get fed there you know and you
get you get well I last time I went is I
was eating food out of a sock that was
and I didn't know what you had to guess
what it is was point for the team point
for the team yeah but I mean that is
really putting yourself out of your
comfort zone that's the only thing I
think if everyone says what you realize
is like how human beings do not like to
be to be out of control not to be in
control of things is not a nice feeling
really well I guess I guess you get um
um hungry and then you start not being
yourself cuz you get a bit bad tempered
when you're hungry what do you call it
hungry hry hungry you do get you do get
hungry I think that the boys were
affected a bit more by that there were
certain personalities that you could see
were really struggle I was thought with
the jungle when they do those challenges
and you think oh I'm going to get going
to get a fry up or whatever and then you
get a plate of rice don't you for all
those hard challenges yeah oh I mean the
the the the worst one was where you can
go out and get treats or something the
to bring back and somebody came back and
we literally had one jelly baby
eat that's an absolute stitch up would
you do it for the
team you no no no I've I've been asked
to do it and I like the idea of camping
out with people I don't know and getting
to know them but it's just the
challenges when you've got to eat
certain things a lot don't I think the
strictly thing I did that that's Would
You released 19 years ago 19 years
strictly W was it really hard wow uh it
was do you know what it it was a lot of
training but it you expect that these
people were multiple world champions you
know that you and also you got to think
do I do I want to look like
a as if I've learned something after on
a Saturday rather than just you you
don't realize in your show like that how
big it is I suppose when you're in that
big bubble cuz there's no real shows
like that I suppose
anymore mean it is amazing thing to do
it's also hard because what the audience
sees no no no would you oh I don't know
I don't know what why wouldn't you do it
then well it looks like really hard work
I would I I would I would genuinely do
it love to be to learn how to dance I I
just love music and the that sort of Na
straight into theer I've seen him I've
seen him dance if anybody needs to do it
it's him I tell you what I would do I
got just Joy it's Joy I got have to do
the Christmas one and I think that's I
guess a bit more Whimsical than the
actual one honestly I got have to do
that last year and I was busy writing
that book so I said I couldn't but maybe
this year I would do it it's absolutely
magical Chistmas one do the Christmas
why don't you do it and I'll do it we'll
do the we could partner each other yes
right usually I can get a link this I've
got no idea it's just a straight cut all
right straight into the beo stew this we
put the lid on it cook it for an hour
and a half and then what we end up with
is one we've got in this pot over here
the pot changes color at the same time
cuz I have only got one of them and I've
only got one of these so then what we're
going to do is make our dumplings this
is some perfectly chopped parsley over
here and then I've got some can you
pinch of salt please yeah oh I love a
dumpling do you always use that pumpkin
pot or is it because it's nearly
Halloween Hall Halloween Halloween
Halloween yes yes I use not festive pot
then well I've got that I've got the
Tomato one oh yeah I mean you have got
some Posh pots hav you I got married on
Halloween pots there some I got married
on Halloween so when I see as soon as I
see a pumpkin it reminds me of me
wedding cuz the night before spent ages
with all my friends hollowing out and
putting the silly faces on pumpkins
pumpkins everywhere a that was an
interesting story wasn't right look you
got the dumplings what You' got to do is
try not to make them too dry so rather
than just oh I'm interested so you don't
roll yours or anything to keep them so
they don't go hard yeah this is to make
them nice and soft but it's the amount
of moisture you put in so put that in
there pop the lid on it Chief
prop and
then you put it in the oven and what a
good hour in the oven when you got the
dopping in and then you
there there you go and then pumkin we've
got another pot this is
more more from a pumpkin to a
cow that I mean that's that's
extraordinary
this is my little pot over here and then
we got Jam that's a Bel is that the one
you just bring out at Christmas and this
is the one just for you lot you see just
just for you feel
honored you lift off the lid the
director calls this a money
shot oh is as well yes Touch of that
look at that crust on those
duins it's naughty and then look at the
crust on those
dumpers it's not a thing you hear say
every day but the thing about it is by
having having the the meat that we
talked about that you get look at that
chunks of it yeah and I think that's
that's what you want really otherwise it
all sorts dissolves it you end up going
hunting tiny little bits of sort of
nothing are it's all from the same
muscle if you buy like that as well so
it it'll bre you know what I am that's
my takeaway from this I'm never going to
buy already cubed up brazing steak ever
again I'm writing a musical with my
friend Phil and it's called history of
meat and we're starting off with two
cavemen discussing where to get it from
he's making this
up
am it starts off with 2K yeah we go
through time all the history of me and
we were talking about how much money the
is in musicals and we said we should
write one my my friends are a musician
and and straight away I said the history
of me and then I started singing songs
about me in the pub and he was recording
them on his phone and um just reminded
me of got oh yeah it's in 2025 I should
write a song called stew so there you
have it classic beef sh and dumplings
done
there we have it oh there you go Chely
thank you go your dumplings you may be
drinking red wine with this what do you
think or a paint of ale or what what do
you drink with this you can drink
whatever you want Chief just oh my gosh
that just I mean that's just melting
that really
is all about the
dumpling B doing dumplings
M it's gone really quiet isn't
it that's a really good sign but that's
it silence at the end of the show there
we go nice ending as well loveely diss
that that's it that's all we got time
for today massive thank you to all my
guests Paul John and of course Su
Le good luck with the books as well and
good luck with the restaurants I'll be
down there see you uh see you back at
the same time next Saturday morning
we'll be jooin my more Super celebrity
chefs more great guests as well and also
we've got singer and songwriter Jack
Savar joining us then until then thanks
for watching bye for now have a great
weekend try that at home